# Tagailo, Dan Vincent

## Fullstack Software Developer

tagailo.danvincent@gmail.com

+639685828627

https://danutagailo.web.app

For the last 9 years Dan has been working on IT industries developing software applications using various technologies for backend and frontend development.

He is a full stack developer responsible for the requirement analysis, UI design and integration, building APIs with integration and unit testing, database design and deployment.

His experience in working various projects using different technologies and frameworks mold his ability to swiftly adapt client requirement and get things done.

### **Experience**

Software Developer - Collabera Digital

Nov 2023 - May 2024

API Development (NodeJs Loopback in typescript). Unit testing (SinonJs, Mocha).

Scheduling and Background Services (BullJobs + ioRedis).

OS Crontab, Shell scripts.

■ GCM-3 Associate Consultant - Atos Syntel

Nov 2021 - Sep 2023

Frontend integration to existing and new feature (Angular).

API Development (NodeJs Azure function-app).

Integration and unit testing (Jest).

Azure Deployment.

Software Developer - First Performance Global

May 2019 - Aug 2021

Frontend development (VueJs).

API Development (NodeJs - Restify, KnexJs ORM).

Integration and unit testing (SinonJs).

Python scripts for loading oneshot data.

Backend Developer - Freelance

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

API Development (NodeJS + Sequelize ORM).

Database design

Deployment (AWS EC2 windows instance running on windows IIS)

Fullstack Software Developer - 4LOOP Inc

*May 2015 – Nov 2018* 

Frontend design and development (Angular1, VueJs).

API Development (NodeJs - Express, Django).

Database design.

Deployment (AWS EC2, Digital Ocean).

Python scripts for loading data.

Lead the development of several projects.

## Software & Technology

- Proficient in: NodeJs, VueJs, QuasarJs, Jest, Sinon, Mocha, Bootstrap, Shell scripts, crontab
- Familiar with: Jira, Azure, AWS(EC2, RDS, S3), Python, Django, PHP, Azure Function apps, Firebase, Angular, Redis, Reactis, JavaSE, Docker
- Operating System: Microsoft Windows, Ubuntu Linux
- Version Control: GIT
- Database: SQL Databases, NoSql(MongoDB, Cosmos DB, Firebase).
- Framework: NodeJs(Loopback/ExpressJs/Restify), VueJs(Quasar, VueBootstrap), ORM(Sequelize, KnexJs).

#### Education

**High School** 2009

Mindanao State University

2014 Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

## **Relevant Projects**

#### Collabera (Metrobank Client) - BFAOC Project

Major in Database Systems

One of the key member of the team responsible for the code structure, like how are things get scaffolded in a proper way, how and where to setup a new code base for the background processing also align package version for compatibility, as well as server activities like resolving build issues and deployment support. Additionally the only one working on the unit test coverage.

Tech Stack: Node (loopback) in typescript, BullJobs, ioRedis, crontab, shell scripts, sinonJs

#### Eviden/Atos (Humana client) - NPD Project

Responsible for building APIs to automate many manual processes of the business including generation of full-blown reports of medical plans.

Tech Stack: Azure Function app (Node), CosmosDB, Azure Devops, Logic apps, Jest.

#### First Performance Global - Auto enrollment MF, Scheduled Jobs

Responsible for building APIs to support new features and also bug fixing to existing applications.

Tech Stack: Vue(Vue-Bootstrap Framework), Restify, NodeJs, Mysql, KnexJs, AWS, Python, Redis, Bull-Jobs, SinonJs, Microservices architecture.

#### 4LOOP Inc - Raise Foundation app

Responsible for the entire development of the app. Basically this is a foundation app built based in Australia to help and prevent child abuse and neglect.

Tech Stack: Angular1, NodeJs, MongoDB, Express, Passport, AWS EC2, AWS S3, Bootstrap, SendGrid, D3.

#### 4LOOP Inc - Symphony

Lead the development of the app. This is a generic core api platform for all our applications. It was designed to support subscription based ecommerce platforms, product ordering, device management and asset management to cater 3D assets from our 3D related applications in house, cms templates and much more.

Tech Stack: VueJs(vuetify), NodeJs, Express, MySQL, Bootstrap, Passport, SendGrid, D3, AWS RDS, AWS S3.

#### ♠ 4LOOP Inc - Equipment Inspection app

Responsible for the backend development of the app and some frontend works. This is a mobile and web app for equipment inspection which helps civil engineers for inspection operations. Tech Stack: VueJs(vuetify), NodeJs, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Passport, SendGrid, D3, Digital Ocean.

#### 4LOOP Inc - Facebook Ads Marketing app

Responsible for the entire development of the api. This is an app to shorten the process of operating Facebook ads marketing.

Tech Stack: VueJs, NodeJs, Express, MySQL, Bootstrap, Digital Ocean.

#### ● 4L00P Inc - Grub2Go

Responsible for the backend development of the app, and some frontend works. This is a mobile app for ordering food like FoodPanda App.

Tech Stack: Ionic, Angular1, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, cordova, google maps.

## **Other Projects**

#### Class Management System for grade school

Responsible for the entire development of the app. This is a web application which helps gradeschool teachers in some operations in school such as enrollment, subject assignment to teachers, grade entry, manage lesson plans, create exams and questionnaires, online examination, view and manage exam results and full-blown grade reporting.

Tech Stack: VueJs(Quasar Framework), Mysql, NodeJS, Express, Apex charts.

#### Enrollment System

Responsible for the entire development app. This is a typical enrollment system built for high school

Tech Stack: AdminLTE bootstrap UI library, JQuery, PHP, Mysql.

#### **●** TER (Teaching Efficiency Rating)

Responsible for the entire development of the app. This is basically a paperless process of teacher/instructor evaluation in our university. It was successfully deployed and used. Tech Stack: AdminLTE bootstrap UI library, JQuery, PHP, Mysql.

#### KAWAL-APP

Responsible for the entire development of the web application part. This app was built to help soldiers(AFP) dependents on the entire process to get financial support when the said soldier dies in combat.

Tech Stack: VueJs(Quasar Framework), Apex charts, Firebase hosting, Firebase Realtime Database, NodeJS, Serverless, cordova, PWA, SPA, APK build.